Happy New Year 2024 to all of you.
Welcome to 2024.
Financial year 2023-24 is going to end in less than a month.
You too must be looking to buy term life insurance to strengthen your income
tax benefits, financial planning and
financial foundation. So,
if you are
thinking of buying term insurance, this
video will be very helpful for you. In this video,
I have compared the top four term plans of the industry
for you, where there is ICICI
's iProtect Smart, ADFC Life
's Click to Protect Super Term Plan,
TA AI's Sampoorna Raksh Supreme Term
Plan and Max Life Insurance's
Smart Secure Plus Term Plan.
Here
you will get a comparison of basic features, a comparison
of riders, a comparison of premiums.
Here you will get a
comparison with benefit illustrations.
In this video, I have explained in detail
your accidental cover, cancer
insurance, permanent disabilities cover,
critical illness benefit, smart exit
benefit, life stage.  How
can I increase my insurance cover? I have compared many other great features of this method. Will
regular premium be good for you or
limited premium? Will the option of Petal A60 be
better for you or will the option of return of
premium be better for you?
I have also explained all these options
in detail, so
watch this video completely. If you like the video, then
definitely subscribe to my YouTube4FFS.
Thank you so much. A strong house
needs a strong foundation. If the foundation is strong, then you
can build not just a house but a big building. Is the foundation of your financial planning
strong? Does your financial
portfolio have term life insurance
because the foundation of financial planning
starts with insurance. You
can see the financial pyramid on the side.
If you have taken insurance, you have taken a
big insurance cover, then the foundation of your
financial planning is
very strong for your family. Like the pyramids of Egypt,
which you can see on the side. But if
you have not taken a big term insurance in your portfolio, then
your entire
financial planning has never been  The opposite can happen,
and the entire family may suffer losses
because, just as a house lasts a
lifetime and extends to future generations
if it is strong, similarly, a
large term life insurance cover will be
useful to your family and even future generations.
If something happens to you,
they won't have to be financially dependent on anyone. All
four companies were started in 2001.
All four companies
began operations in India in 2001 because that's when
IRDA
allowed private insurance companies to do business.
Talking about the claim settlement
ratio, all three companies have
excellent settlement ratios. ICICI
is the most prestigious company this year. If you look at the
average claim settlement ratio of the last 10 years, it ranks
number one among 24 companies.
If you
look at the average claim settlement ratio of 10 years, compare it to every year,
ADFC's claim
settlement ratio is 99.3.  It
is at 99.0 and Max Life Insurance is at 99.5. So,
all the companies have a
claim settlement ratio of up to 9899, ​​so
this will be considered an excellent claim settlement ratio.
If we talk about asset under management, then
ICICI Prance Life Insurance is a
company worth 1 lakh crore, ADFC is a company worth 2.38 lakh
crore. If we talk about Tata AE, then
Tata AE Life Insurance has an asset of 81000 crore
and Max Life Insurance has an
asset of 8857 crore rupees. So all the four
companies are very big companies, they have been
working in the market for 23 years. The claim settlement
ratio of all is good and the plans also, all the four are the
best term
plans in the industry. Its entry is so that any person from 18 years
to 65 years can
purchase this policy. Any person in the
sense who is healthy, fit, financially healthy
and fit, physically healthy and fit.
Financially healthy means filing ITR and having
income proof.  Only those who have a salary
slip can take a term insurance policy. Those who do
not have income proof
cannot take a Payo term plan. Physical
health means being completely healthy. It is not necessary that there is
any pre-existing disease or disability.
In that case, a term plan is not available.
Education is also checked, income proof is also
checked and physical health is also checked
through a medical test. So, if you are
eligible for all three, then even if you are 18 years old,
you can purchase the policy. A
person up to the maximum age of 65 years can
purchase this policy. All these companies have
different options in all the plans, like there is a
return of premium option and an income
option. They can have different entry ages,
from 18 to, for example, if there is a return
of premium, then you will get cover up to the age of 55 or up to the age of 60.
But in the basic sum
insurance cover, a person up to the age of 65 years can
purchase this policy,
depending on the financial underwriting
because a person between 18 and 35 years is eligible.
No, he gets insurance cover up to 25 times his income,
but when he turns 60, he
gets insurance cover only five times his income. So this also
matters a lot with your age because at that
time, suppose the earning age left at 60 years
is reduced considerably, but the
earning age of a 25 year old person is
more than the age of 60 years, hence he is
eligible for more insurance cover.
Talking about the policy term,
you can take a term policy up to 99 years in ICICI PRL and Tata AE Life.
You will get coverage up to 85 years in Max Life and HDFC.
Talking about the minimum sum,
in all four policies you will have to take a minimum sum of Rs 50
lakh. Talking about the maximum sum, there is no
limit on premium
payment. In ICICI PRL, you will get the
option of single premium, but the
policy term there will be 20 years only if
you take single premium. In limited pay,
you will get 5 years, 7 years and 10 years.
Suppose you have to pay for six years.  Or if you want to pay for 8 years, then
you will not get this option,
but you can pay for 5 years, you can pay for 7 years, you
can pay for 10 years and if
you want to pay on regular basis every year, you can do it
and if your age is 60, then the option of till age 60 is
also given in this policy. If we talk about
STFC, then there is single premium,
regular premium, five years and above,
you can select any one 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11,
12. In this way, you
can select any premium payment term. Similarly,
in TA also, there is a similar option, there is single
premium, regular premium, five years and
above. If you want to select any premium payment, then
you can do it.
In Max Life Insurance, you will get 5 years, 10 years,
12 years, 15 years, there is an option of pay till 60. There is an
option of regular pay. Suppose
in Max Life, you have to pay premium for 8 years, 11 years,
14 years, this
option is not available.  You will get it but you will
get the option of Pay 10, 12, 15 and Pay till 60. If
you want to pay regular premium every year, you
can pay. Talking about the payment mode,
you can pay annually, quarterly,
semi-annually and
monthly mode. Similarly, in all the
policies, the waiver of premium is available.
In ICICI, you will get the inbuilt option of waiver of
premium. If you suffer from permanent
disabilities, you do
not need to pay a separate premium. If you become
permanently disabled, in that case,
all your future premium
increases will be waived. In HDFC Life
Insurance, if you suffer from a
disability
or a critical illness, the premium
payment is waived. You will have to take it as a rider,
for which you will have to pay an additional
premium. The waiver of
premium option is not available in TAI.
In Max Life Insurance, in case of critical illness and
dismemberment, your premiums will be
waived but
you will have to pay an additional premium for it.  If we talk about
terminal illness, then terminal illness
means that
a doctor and a medical practitioner of the medical company from which you have taken the policy,
give in writing that within six months
this patient or customer will die due to
this particular disease, then the
customer gets a certain amount of
insurance cover during his lifetime. Suppose you have
taken an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore,
suppose if you have taken an ICICI policy
then you will get the entire Rs 1 crore. If a
terminal illness is diagnosed, if we talk about
STFC Life then also you will get Rs 1 crore. If we
talk about Tata then Tata will give 50%, that is, you will get Rs 50
lakh on diagnosis of terminal illness. The remaining Rs 50 lakh will be given on
death. In Max Life
Insurance, you will get the terminal illness benefit of up to Rs 1 crore
immediately. Now
suppose you have purchased a policy of Rs 5 crore
and a terminal illness is
diagnosed, then there is
no mention of ICICI in the case of terminal illness.  It has been said that
some limit has not been mentioned, that is, they will
probably give you the full 5 crores,
but if we talk about STFC, then the limit is Rs
2 crore, you will get Rs 1 crore on terminal illness, the
remaining Rs 4 crore will be given on death,
in Tata as I told you and in Mass Life
Insurance, you get up to Rs 1 crore on terminal
illness diagnosis, the remaining Rs 4 crore will be given to
you on death, if we
talk about critical
illness benefit in the policy, then there is a critical illness benefit,
you will have to
buy it as a rider, terminal illness
is inbuilt in all the four policies, you
can do critical illness rider, so
in ICICI you will get
34 critical illness benefits,
where if you are diagnosed with any of the 34 diseases, then the
amount you have purchased will be paid to
you, if we talk about
STFC, then you
get cover of 19 critical illness benefits, but if you
take Health Plus or Grader, then there you will get
60  You will get the benefit of critical illness.
In TA AI, you get the benefit of 40 critical illnesses under the
name of Crit Care.
And in Max Life Insurance, you
can avail the benefit of 64 critical illnesses.
This will cover five minor critical illnesses and the
remaining 59 major critical illnesses.
Max Life Insurance
also provides five critical illness options:
Platinum Plus, Gold Plus, Gold. There
are five such options where you
can avail the benefit of 64 critical illnesses and
22 critical illnesses.
Along with this, in Gold Plus and Platinum Plus,
you also get the benefit of
total and permanent disability due to disabilities.
You can avail the benefit up to the amount of CIDR rider you have taken for Critical Illness Plus Dismemberment Man Rider. The option of
return of premium is not provided in iProtect Smart in the ICICI portal.
For this, you have to take a separate policy
called Return of Premium.
You can avail of a term plan as a separate
plan, but in this particular
plan that I am comparing,
return of premium is
not available. In the plans of the other three companies, these options are available in different ways, namely,
Return of Premium, Live
Plus, Trop, Term
Return of Premium.
Talking about Smart Exit, Smart Exit
means what many people
call a free or free cost term plan, while some
call it a zero cost term plan. This
means that after a particular year,
if you wish to withdraw all your deposited money,
you can do so. This is an inbuilt
feature, and you do not have to pay any separate premium.
In ICICI Prudential, you can exercise this option after 25 years. The
condition for this is
that your insurance cover should be at least Rs 60
lakh. The insurance cover is Rs 60 lakh or more.
After 25 years, if
you wish to close the policy by collecting the entire premium you have paid,
you can do so.  In ADFC Life,
you will get the option of Smart Exit after 30 years
for which the minimum policy
term is also 30 years.
Smart Exit option is not available in Tata Life.
In Max Life Insurance also,
this option is given after 30 years that if you
want to withdraw all your deposited money, you
can do so, hence this plan is
also called Zero Cost or Free of Cost Term Plan.
Talking about Life Stage Protection
Benefit, as the age increases,
different events of life take place like marriage,
birth of the first child,
birth of the second child, then if you
want to increase your insurance cover with Life Stage, then
you can increase it. Suppose you are getting married, then
suppose you have taken an
insurance cover of Rs 1 crore, then you can increase your insurance cover by Rs 50
or maximum Rs 50 lakh. Then you can increase your insurance
cover by Rs 25 lakh on the
birth of the first child or even on the birth of the second child
under Life Stage Benefit. If
you have taken a loan in Tata Life, then the loan amount will be refunded.  If there is an amount,
you are given the
opportunity to increase the insurance cover equal to that amount.
This option is available in Max Life
Insurance. This Smart Life
Stage Production Benefit is
not available, but is available in all the other three plans.
Disability cover is available as a rider.
Such a rider
is not available in ICICI. It comes in the invoice,
but there only the premium increase is waived,
you do not get the additional amount.
In ADFC Life, if you have taken a
normal insurance cover of suppose ₹ crore or
you have taken a permanent disability cover of ₹ crore, in that
case, if you become permanently disabled, then you will continue to get
1% of ₹ crore per month for the
next 10 years while you are alive
and after that, if you die, then
your insurance cover of 1
crore is also available for death benefit. So here, the 1 per cent
rider that you have taken is available,
you will get it as a rider on additional premium. If we
talk about TI also, then the
rider is available by paying additional premium.  You
can utilize it as a cover, here you will get the entire
money together, suppose you have taken a normal cover of one crore,
you have taken a
disability cover of 1 crore, there is partial
disability, disability
occurs, in that case you will get the entire one share together,
after that if there is death then
that second one share will also be available,
in Max Life Insurance also it will come as a rider
but this critical illness
CIDR which I told you will come with that rider, so
there
your premium will become very expensive due to critical illness,
suppose if you go to take one crore then if
critical illness also comes along with it then it will become
very expensive, it will become more than your basic
premium,
but suppose you have taken a critical illness benefit of 10 lakhs,
along with this you will
get this benefit that if there is a disability then
you will get a benefit up to 10 lakhs for the
duration of this rider, if we
talk about the option of spouse cover, then here
you will get Tata End  There is
no option of spouse cover in ICICI. There
is an option of spouse cover in HDFC. Suppose the husband has
taken an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore.
You will have to select this at the time of inception
and suppose he has selected that he wants spouse
cover. Now suppose the husband has taken an insurance cover of Rs
1 crore, the wife will get it and the nominee will get it.
After that, the insurance cover up to Rs 50 lakh will
start, that is, the
insurance cover of Rs 50 lakh will be valid. Now,
if he dies, the remaining Rs 50
lakh will be given to his sons or any legal
heirs who will be the nominee. So,
you get spouse cover up to Rs 50 lakh or Rs 50 lakh. If we
talk about HDFC Life or
Max Life Insurance,
you can take spouse cover up to Rs 50 lakh there too. If we
talk about increasing insurance cover,
then you will
not get the option of increasing in ICICI STFC Tata and
according to the life stage benefit that I mentioned,
you can increase the insurance cover on the birth of your married children
because this is an
option available in Max Life.  It was not available in me
but there is an option in Max Life,
your insurance cover will increase at a simple interest rate of 5%
for the next 20 years, suppose you have taken an
insurance cover of 1 crore, next year the
cover will become 1 crore 5 lakh, then it will become 1
crore 10 lakh, in this way
your insurance cover will increase up to 2 crore, it will
increase by 5%, now suppose after 20 years if
you die then the nominee will
get 2 crores and income
option is not given in ADFC, in this the
benefit of life income is given that when you turn
55, 60 or 65, at that time you
can take your insurance as income from 0.01% to 0.15% every year, so suppose
your income will start at 60 years, if you have taken
cover till 85 then till 85 years you will get a certain
amount as income every year for the next 25 years,
which amount you can take as income  But the
death benefit you are taking will be
deducted. Talking about the Accelerated Critical
Illness Benefit,
it is not available in ADF Tata. It is available in 34
Critical Illness Benefit in ICICI and 40 Critical Illness Benefit in Max.
You have to take this Accelerated Critical Illness at the time of inception. Its premium is
less than the Comparative Critical Illness Rider.
But what happens here is that
suppose you took an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore and in that
you took Accelerated
Critical Illness of Rs 10 lakh. Now if any critical
illness is diagnosed to you,
you will get Rs 1 lakh immediately but now that
benefit will remain only Rs 90 lakh. But
if you have bought a Separate Critical Illness Rider
and a Critical Illness of Rs 10 lakh
is diagnosed and you get Rs 1 lakh, there is
no impact on the death benefit but
its premium is comparatively higher. Let's
talk about Option Two.  Take benefit in
installment, that is, in case of death of brother, then the nominee
wants the entire money in one go, that he
wants to take it as an income for the next 5 years, 10 years, 15 years, 30 years or
you can take it partially as lump sum and the rest as income, then
these options are given to you, this
is available in the products of all the companies, like
HDFC, Tata Max, which is, HDFC is
giving you the option of income from 5 years to 15 years, is giving the option of income for 10
years, Max Ta is giving you the option of income for 5 years,
lump sum is being given to all of you,
but ICICI is giving a stand out option
where you can take income for 30 years
and can also get a discount of up to 30%
on the premium. In all the other three companies,
you have the option of taking this death benefit installment,
but you do
not get any rebate on the premium, but ICICI
also gives you a discount of 15, 20 and 30%. To
know more about this feature, visit
my  It is
available in YouTube1. Suppose you
want to take a break in premium once or twice, that is, in a particular year you do
not want to pay premium, say after 11 years or 22
years. Suppose you do
not pay premium in the 11th year, even then your
policy will continue during that year. Even if you
die, you will get death benefit.
Secondly, if we talk about top up, then the top up
option is not available in IF.
This top up option is available in TA. From 5 onwards,
your basic sum keeps increasing
and it probably goes up to a maximum of 50 lakhs.
Similarly, in Max Life also, you get 100% of the
base sum.
You can top up up to a maximum of ₹ 1 lakh.
Talking about the accident cover of your insurance cover, the
benefit of accidental rider is available in all four companies.
You can add accidental cover as a rider.
In ICICI, you
can add accidental cover up to ₹ 1 crore. In Max Life, the maximum
You can add accidental cover up to Rs 1 crore.
This is the limit of cover there.
Only HDFC Life Insurance offers
cancer as a rider. If
you
want to take a rider for a particular cancer,
you will get cancer insurance cover at a very cheap premium. You should
definitely add it. Today,
it is a very serious disease and requires a huge
amount to cure it. But
here you will get the policy once and the
premium will not increase every year and
you will get it at a cheap price. So, if you
want to add cancer cover, you can do it.
Talking about surrender benefit,
you do not get surrender benefit in regular premium.
If you pay limited premium,
minimum you pay two premiums. In that
case, your surrender value is generated
and you get the surrender benefit. In maths life
insurance, you get the surrender benefit
after the premium payment term.
If you have taken a return of premium
policy, then the amount of surrender benefit is
comparatively
higher. Let's talk about grace in the policy.  Regarding
premium, you get 30 days grace premium,
suppose your premium is due,
you get 30 days extra, there is a
benefit for paying premium, there is
survival benefit, which means
you do not get any money if it happens because
this is a pure term plan and if you win the survival benefit,
you do not get any money back.
Yes, if you have taken the life income option in Tata, then
you get income in the form of survival benefit
and if you are
taking the option of written off premium, then the
money paid is returned to you in the form of maturity.
Talking about death benefit, you get the
insurance cover in the death benefit.
If you have taken any rider, then you
also get the benefits of the rider. If that
particular rider like accidental cover is taken in case of
death in an accident, then you
get double insurance cover.
Talking about the grace period in the plan,
if you have taken the policy in monthly mode,
quarterly mode or semi-monthly mode, then you get a grace period of
15 days, otherwise you
get 30 days. The free period is of 15 days.
If you
want to cancel the policy due to any reason, then there is a
free period of 15 days. It is the same in all the companies.
You also get a revival period of 5 years.
If for some reason you are
not able to pay the premium on time for one or two years, then you can cancel the premium for
two years together.  You
can revive the policy by paying the premium as well.
You are given a full 5 years time for revival.
Now let us see the comparison of premium,
if we take an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore
and we make the premium payment regularly i.e. pay it
every year and
if we take insurance cover till the age of 85, then
what will be the premium in ICICI, ADFC, Max and Tata. The red colour you will
see is of ICC, blue you
will see is of ADFC, then Tata, then green you will see the
colour of Max. The age limit is given for 30, 35, 40, 45, 50,
55 and 60. If we compare at different ages, for
example, if you purchase a policy of
Rs 1 crore at the age of 30, then you will see that the
premium of SDFC will be Rs
2588, you will get it for ICICI for Rs 22101, STFC will be Rs
2078, you will get it for Max Life Insurance for Tata and Rs 450. As the
age increases,
you will see it will be Rs
9000, then Rs 29, then SDA etc.  27 and 27 you will
get Max and Tata,
then 39 38 35 and 36 so if you see here,
Tata is getting cheaper at the age of 40
comparatively here as the age increases
you will see a little less margin
as the age increases, for example suppose the
age reaches 55 then the opposite will happen that
you will get ICICI cheaper, Max will be
more expensive but if the age decreases then
ICICI will be more expensive, Max will be
cheaper so comparatively age wise you
can see how much
premium will be charged at which age, in regular pay of 1 crore
now we are looking at the second option of 1 crore
but this time the premium increases for 10 years only
and you are taking coverage till the age of 85 so
here you will see that you have to pay 57000 for 10 years
this premium is with GST
and you will get coverage till the age of 85,
premium of 56000 for 55 years in Ara
ADAC in ICICI is coming at 57000
because inbuilt in ICICI you  Waiver of
rider is also available if there is a terminal illness
or permanent disability,
in that case, you are getting Rs. 50,000 of T&C
in Max Life. Here
you will see that at Rs. 67, 35, then
HDFC is taking Rs. 73, Tata is taking Rs. 64, then
Max Life Insurance is taking Rs. 65, so
comparatively you will find Tata's premium cheaper.
As soon as you reach Rs. 45, 50,
ICICI will appear cheaper to you and at that
age you will always
find ICICI cheaper. There is another option in ICICI
that if you take death benefit in installments, then
you also get a discount up to Rs. 30,
I have already told you about it,
I will get
ICICI.
Installment option is available in all the other four companies as well,
but you will not get discount there,
only ICICI is giving discount
if you purchase the policy in the premium payment term of 5 years.
If you are financially
healthy  If you are an H customer and
want to reduce headache by paying limited premium, then
if you pay premium per year, then here you will
always find Tata's 30 percent cheaper.
You will find Tata's cheaper in almost all age groups.
At 5 percent till 45 percent,
you will find ICICI's. So if you are looking at 45 and
above, then you can also see ICICI's
limited amount in almost limited amounts, 5 percent and 10 percent. If you
take the discount factor, you will find it cheaper on this too. And you have
already seen the rest of the features.
You can see which one has which feature and which rider's benefits. So,
one thing is that you should buy an insurance policy at a lower age
because as the premium
increases, you will see that the
premium also increases very rapidly.
Buying insurance at a younger age will be cheaper and beneficial for you.
If we talk about buying insurance of Rs 2 crore, with
coverage up to 85 percent on 10 years premium, then in premium you
will see that Rs 2 crore is available for Rs 96,000
and  How much were you getting one crore rupees for? One
crore for lakh,000,
sorry, let's see,
in 10 p, you were getting one crore
rupees for 57,000, one crore insurance
and two crore insurance for
96,000, if you go for the bigger one,
you get a discount as well, it is a bit
cheaper comparatively and here
also if you see, you will get
Max LA insurance cheaper for 91,000, both Max and Tata almost for 30, 35, 30
crore
insurance, you will
get it cheaper for 40 crore, so here for 2
crore, you can see from 40 that
you start getting cheaper ICICI insurance
compared to other products, you can see according to what
kind of problem you are taking, how you purchase riders,
but one thing is that if you purchase at a young age,
you will get a more comparatively cheaper plan,
now let's understand the benefits of four products
together, so we are taking the first illustration.  This is the
iProduct Smart of ICICI Prudential and here you will
see that you have to pay a
premium of Rs 5146. All these four
options that I have taken are non-smoker, 35 years old, the
policy term is 35 years, which means the
policy will run till the age of 70, the premium has to be
paid for only 10 years and this has been taken with the rider, so
now you will see that you will have to pay a
premium of Rs 7778, sorry income,
here I have
put an income option of 30 years in the ICICI,
if there is death then the
nominee will not get the same amount, he will
get Rs 7778 as income for 30 years, so here
he is also getting a % discount, so
now you see, plus I have taken an
accelerated critical illness cover of Rs
10 lakh, it means wherever the
word accelerated is used, so suppose
if the disease is diagnosed then you will get Rs 1 lakh, then
Rs 1 lakh will be reduced from the T.
Accidental death cover of 1 crore is also
taken in this policy.
Now you see here, the premium will be ₹ 681.
Basic GST is of 804.
You will get tax rebate in ATC.
You will have to pay GST of 865/956 for critical illness and
in section AD of income tax, there is a section of medi claim
where you get tax benefit up to 25000.
You will get this rebate in that.
This will be available in AC. This will be available in 8D.
Accidental death benefit cover is also of
13700 with GST of
2466 and rider benefit will also
get tax benefit in ATC. Your annual
premium will be
6472. Without GST, your
premium will be 5246. GST will be charged
of 9226. If you see in ICICI, till now 7.72 crore lives have been
covered. Out of this, a
benefit of 1 lakh crore has been paid till now.
You get tax benefit in bonus etc. Now let's see.  At the age of 35, I
took the all-in-one option, accidental cover is
also included in it, so now
what income are you taking here, monthly income,
which I told you is a
natural cover of one crore, even if there is death, one crore will be
available, even if there is a terminal illness, one
crore will be available, terminal illness is inbuilt in it, if there is an
accidental death benefit,
one crore plus one or two crore will be available, if there is a
critical illness, one lakh will be available, the
cover for critical illness will be for 30 years,
now you see here, the pure
insurance cover of one crore is
available to you only for 26000, that is,
with GST, it is available only for 31000
because there is a discount on 30,
accidental cover benefit is available for 1666,
now take a look once in this pure,
terminal illness cover is included, if terminal
illness is diagnosed, one crore will be available immediately
or if there is a power of premium or permanent
disabilities  If disability occurs
due to an accident, the premium increase will be waived.
This is inbuilt. There is no need to take a separate rider. There will be
no separate premium.
Accidental death benefit rider of Rs.
1 crore is available for Rs. 12821. You have got a
critical illness cover for Rs. 12821. The total
premium comes to Rs. 1000. This is ICICI potential.
10 years premium on 35 years. The policy
will run for Rs. 1 crore. Click
to see ADFC Super Pay 10 years premium
and here I will explain to you. The
basic cover is of Rs. 1 crore. Is the
critical illness cover also taken for 10 years
or for 35 years? The
premium is made for 10 years. The policy term is
also 10 years. A cover of Rs. 10 lakh is taken.
Income benefit on accidental
disabilities is a cover of Rs. 1 crore.
Income benefit for 35 years means that
if disability occurs, then
% of Rs. 1 crore will be given.  ₹ lakh per month will go to the nominee for the next 10 years
or to the person himself during his lifetime
and accidental cover of one crore has also been taken for the
next 55 years, so the
premium for pure insurance cover is Rs. 43000
with GST and Rs. 51000,
whereas after discount in IIC it was coming to Rs. 000, for
critical illness it is coming to Rs. 2614 only
because it is covering for only 10 years, the
income benefit will come to Rs. 7700 and GST will give
you Rs. 10 lakh per month
and after including all the remaining riders,
you will finally have to pay a premium of Rs.
73791. Here you will see that after
paying premium for 10 years, there is a
natural cover of Rs. 1 crore. The policy cancellation value is also
visible to you here.
Simply put, if you pay
premium for 10 years of Rs. 35, the
policy
will run for 35 years. There is a normal cover of Rs. 1 crore and
accidental cover of Rs. 1 crore is done.  Here
you are also given disability cover of
Rs 1 crore in Rs 10100, if disability occurs, it
is worth Rs 1 crore in just Rs 6100 and
critical illness
benefit of 40 critical illnesses in Rs 11470,
premium for 35 years is made for 10 years only,
in ADFC the premium is made for 10 years
but the policy was also running for 10 years only, the
premium will run for 35 years, here the basic premium will be Rs
0000 along with GST, rider premium will be Rs
000000, you will have to pay Rs 000000, you
can see the features here, if you want to see minimum guarantee surrender
value etc. then you can see, let's go
towards Max Life Insurance, the
same is taken in Max Life, the cover is of Rs
1 crore, waiver premium is
extra, if you get a critical illness, the
premium will be waived, accidental
cover is of Rs 1 crore, it will last for 35 years
and here we see the basic, you get Rs 000,
accidental cover premium in Rs 986
Critical illness benefit is available for Rs.
000, that is, Platinum Plus is not taken,
Gold Plus Ltd. 2 critical illnesses are covered
plus disabilities are also covered in it, in that
cover of Rs. 10 lakh, even if one is disabled, then only Rs.
10 lakh will be available and even if there is critical illness, then also Rs.
10 lakh will be available, the total
premium will be Rs. 000, you
can see the premium here, you can see the insurance cover
here, the surrender value
starts after the premium payment term, after 30 years
you also had a facility to take the full amount,
you
can also see that facility in smart exit benefit,
but for that the minimum policy
term should have been 40 years and if the policy term was 40 years
then you would have
also seen the smart exit benefit, so
keep a little attention to the term and condition,
these are the four plans as per your need, you have
seen the illustrations of all four, you have seen the premium, you have seen the
feature summary in different premium payment terms, I
hope you liked the video,
my illustration and all  You must have liked the explanation, if you
liked it then I will help
you in more videos of my financial help
which will help you in planning and if you
want to purchase a policy from me,
life insurance, mediclaim etc.
motor insurance of any company then you can contact me
on 9909 4341, mobile number is
also given in the description, thank you so much, so
finally I am surprised, all four
companies are good, all four products are good, it is a
top product, claim settlement ratio
is excellent, you have seen a lot of options, you have
seen the benefit of live stay, you have seen the benefit of waiver of
premium, you have
seen the benefit of critical illness, you are getting accidental cover, you are getting
cover for partial disabilities,
you have been given cancer benefit,
you have been given the option of smart exit and
you are also getting tax benefit in all the policies, and
I have explained all the best options, premium and everything in details, I
hope your financial news, for this the
most important thing is
term insurance and health insurance, in that
taking the decision of term insurance
If you liked this video very much, then
I have
more than 2 videos on YouTube which will
help you in taking financial health and financial decisions. Once again, best wishes for the New Year.
Jai
Hind.